https://www.emdrhap.org/content/trauma-recovery-hap-privacy-policy/

Getting Involved
How YOU can make a difference!
Account Support
Volunteer Login
TRN®
What Do TRN® Associations Do?
About
What is EMDR?
Getting Involved
How YOU can make a difference!
Account Support
Volunteer Login
TRN®
What Do TRN® Associations Do?
About
What is EMDR?
Trauma Recovery/HAP Privacy Policy
EMDR Humanitarian Assistance Programs, Inc.
Privacy Policy
Introduction
EMDR Humanitarian Assistance Programs, Inc. (“Trauma Recovery/HAP”) is a non-profit organization devoted to providing effective trauma treatment to victims of natural disasters and other catastrophic events through training and development of local Trauma Recovery Network® (“TRN”) chapters. When you volunteer for a TRN chapter, become a faculty volunteer, register as a training participant, or make an online purchase or donation, you will be required to provide some or all of the following information: your name, email address, zip code, telephone number, mailing address, licensure information, credit card information, and a username and password. In addition, you may choose to provide Trauma Recovery/HAP with additional information, including: your education, professional experience, employment status and volunteer interests.
The purpose of this privacy policy is to inform you about the types of data gathered, how the information collected is used, and how you can update your communications preferences. By visiting our website at emdrhap.org, you are accepting the practices of this privacy policy. Please read this policy carefully to understand how we handle your Personally Identifiable Information (PII).
Collection of Information
Trauma Recovery/HAP collects information automatically when you visit our website via Google Analytics, and any information you willingly provide when you contact us via contact form or sign up for our newsletter. We only use cookies via Google Analytics to evaluate website performance and facilitate the registration process, not for tracking purposes.
Information we collect via Google Analytics may include:
IP address
Location (City and country)
Computer and device information (OS, mobile device type, browser and version used, service provider, and other technical identifiers)
Demographics (gender, age)
Interests
Referring URLs, keywords used to reach our site, pages of our site that you visited, and the order in which you browsed our site.
Behavior (Date and time you visited our site, frequency of your visits, duration of time you spent on our site)
We are required to provide certain information about you to EMDR International Association (“EMDRIA”) in order to maintain our status as an EMDRIA-Approved Training Provider. This information includes, but is not limited to: participant name, degree info, license number, mailing address, telephone number, email address, date of completion of basic training program, and completed trainer, practicum and consultation evaluation forms. By participating in our training programs, you agree to the disclosure of this information to EMDRIA.
Use of Information
Trauma Recovery/HAP uses information collected in the following ways to:
Provide you the product or service you requested;
Improve our website to better meet your needs;
Improve user experience on the website;
Respond to your inquiries or comments; and
Provide you with requested newsletters or other marketing materials.
Disclosure of Information
We understand we have a responsibility to handle sensitive personal data carefully and consider it confidential, unless we have your permission to share or publish information. We do not sell or trade the information we collect to third parties; however, we may disclose certain pertinent information to third parties to assist us in delivering the product or service you requested. This may include outside consultants, vendors, or independent contractors with whom we acquire assistance. We will also provide information to authorities if required by law.
Trauma Recovery/HAP uses various social media platforms for branding and publicity. Please use care when posting comments or personal information on our company pages. This information is open to the public. Refer to the privacy policies of these social media platforms for further information.
Facebook Privacy Policy
LinkedIn Privacy Policy
All employees of Trauma Recovery/HAP are under individual written confidentiality agreements to use information for its intended purpose and as directed by management.
Retention of Information
We will retain your information indefinitely.  Upon request, we provide donors with their giving history and participants with their certificates from past completed events.  However, you have the right to request removal of your PII at anytime.  Just call or email us at admin@emdrhap.org.
Data Security
Truama Recovery/HAP uses a variety of administrative practices and industry standard technical safeguards to ensure the security of your information. Although we use the necessary technology to protect your information, internet transmissions are never completely secure. Security measures we may administer include, but are not limited to:
Firewalls
Proxy servers
SSL & encryption
Username & password management
Network access controls
Confidentiality Agreements
Office security system & video cameras
Self-hosted servers
Two-step email security
Anti-virus software
In the event of a data breach, if we suspect any of your personal information may have been accessed, we will attempt to notify you within seven (7) business days of us discovering the breach. You will be contacted via email, and a notice will be posted to our website.
Your Privacy Choices
If you prefer not to receive newsletters or marketing materials from Trauma Recovery/HAP, you can email us, and we will remove you from our mailing list.
You have the right to access, change, or request removal of your PII. Just call us or email us.
You can update your Google privacy settings and control your ads preferences. Visit Google’s Privacy page and the NAI Consumer Opt Out page to learn more.
Third Party Links
Trauma Recovery/HAP uses third party links on its website. These include links to our partners, customers, news articles, and any other information we believe you will enjoy or find informative. We encourage you to review the privacy policies of each of those websites before providing any information to them.
Changes to Our Privacy Policy
Trauma Recovery/HAP reserves the right to change this Privacy Policy at any time. You can view changes to this policy on this page.
Children Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA)
Trauma Recovery/HAP complies with the Children’s Online Privacy Protection Act (COPPA). We do not market to children under the age of 13 years old or willingly collect personal information from children. Please contact us if you believe we have unintentionally acquired information about your child. We are happy to investigate and delete information if we find it.
California Online Privacy Protection Act (CalOPPA)
Trauma Recovery/HAP complies with CalOPPA, and we agree to the following:
You can visit our website anonymously.
A link to this Privacy Policy is available in the footer section of our website and added upon its creation.
The link to this Privacy Policy is easily identifiable and contains the word “Privacy.”
Any changes to our Privacy Policy will be posted on our Privacy Policy Page.
You have the right to change your personal information and can do so by calling us or emailing us.
We adhere to the practices included in this Privacy Policy.
For more information, you can visit the CFC’s website: www.consumercal.org.
Contact Information
If you have any questions or concerns regarding our Privacy Policy, please email us or call us at (203) 288-4450. You can also reach us by mail at the following address:
EMDR Humanitarian Assistance Programs, Inc.
Trauma Recovery/HAP2911 Dixwell Avenue, Ste. 201Hamden, CT 06518
Contact:Phone: (203) 288-4450Fax: (203) 288-4060Email: admin@emdrhap.org
Follow Us:
Show Your Support:
DONATE NOW
Terms of Use | Privacy Policy
Copyright © 2020 Trauma Recovery/Humanitarian Assistance Programs. All rights reserved.
